<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="uwm_bar_unstable_v1">
  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2026 UWM Contributors

    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person
    obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation
    files (the "Software"), to deal in the Software without
    restriction, including without limitation the rights to use,
    copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or
    sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
    Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following
    conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including
    the next paragraph) shall be included in all copies or
    substantial portions of the Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND,
    EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES
    OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND
    NONINFRINGEMENT.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT
    HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY,
    WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
    FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR
    OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <interface name="zwp_uwm_bar_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="UWM bar manager">
      A global interface used by bar clients to receive workspace
      state and focused window title from the UWM compositor.

      One instance is created per output to support multi-monitor.
    </description>

    <request name="get_workspace_group">
      <description summary="get workspace group for an output">
        Create a workspace group object for the given output.
        If output is NULL, the group covers all workspaces.
      </description>
      <arg name="output" type="object" interface="wl_output" allow-null="true"/>
      <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="zwp_uwm_workspace_group_v1"/>
    </request>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the bar manager"/>
    </request>
  </interface>

  <interface name="zwp_uwm_workspace_group_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="workspace group for an output">
      Reports workspace state and focused window title for a
      specific output. Events are sent in batches terminated
      by a done event.
    </description>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the workspace group"/>
    </request>

    <event name="workspace">
      <description summary="workspace state">
        Announces a workspace on this output. Sent at startup and
        on changes. The active flag is 1 if this is the current
        workspace on the output, 0 otherwise. The occupied flag
        is 1 if the workspace has any windows on it.
      </description>
      <arg name="id" type="uint"/>
      <arg name="active" type="uint"/>
      <arg name="occupied" type="uint"/>
    </event>

    <event name="focused_title">
      <description summary="focused window title">
        The title of the currently focused window on the output
        associated with this workspace group.
      </description>
      <arg name="title" type="string"/>
    </event>

    <event name="done">
      <description summary="batch complete">
        Marks the end of a batch of workspace and title updates.
        The client should process all previous events in the batch
        before redrawing.
      </description>
    </event>
  </interface>
</protocol>
